Avinash Rijal

Full stack web developer and DevOps Engineer

10110
Bangkok, Thailand
(+66) 0916667535
avinashrijal@gmail.com

MYSELF

Hi, I am Avinash Rijal. I am an experienced web developer and my goal is to dedicate myself to producing quality work. I am a fast learner and very flexible with work hours. I can work under pressure and I have successfully worked in an environment where customers were going through tough times and needed recovery and had deadlines to catch up to.

EXPERIENCE

CrossOver, Nepal — Full-stack developer

Aug 2018 - Dec 2020

Started as a Laravel + Vue junior developer. Gradually started working and handling CI/CD pipelines on gitlab. Most of the tech stacks I learnt were in internal projects and their clients apps. I got some experience with unit and integration tests and then I moved to MERN stack on the next project from the client which was assigned by dzango to me.

EightBit, Nepal — Full-stack developer

Jan 2021 - Apr 2022

I migrated to EightBit at the start of 2021. I started working under the client Hiboo with a new contract from EightBit. My main stack was MERN and I was also assigned the role of maintaining the pipelines and servers. I got more in-depth knowledge of DevOps and MERN stack. I gained significant experience for E2E and unit testing.

Hiboo, France - MERN stack developer

Aug 2019 - April 15

I was assigned to Hiboo as a MERN stack developer under the contract via Dzango. I had some hands-on experience with enterprise level web app and got more exposure to Node, Mongo, React and GraphQL here. Also, I got more experience on handling the REST API and doing tasks in Scrum. I learn about unit testing, integration testing and E2E tests in cypress on Hiboo. It was a great learning curve and I feel proud to help grow the next leading startup business in France.

Oozou, Thailand - Full stack developer

April 2022 - Present

I have been part of Oozou since 2022. I have been appointed as Full-stack developer and currently I am working as a Full-stack javascript developer. My daily roles involve maintaining and implementing features of Oozou internal projects and handling bug fixes. Currently working in client projects based on contract.

EDUCATION

Acharya Institutes Of Graduate Studies, Bangalore, India — Bachelors Degree in Computer Applications

2015 - 2018

I graduated from the Affiliated college of Bangalore University in India. It provided me with a platform for learning many things with a multicultural platform and very intelligent lecturers. This was the time I was very actively participating in many hackathons and tech events.

Sudur Paschimanchal Academy, Dhangadhi, Nepal — *High School*

2013 - 2015

High school was a bit of a learning curve for me. Provided me the basic knowledge of programming and different algorithms for programming.

PROJECTS

Studytweaks — Community driven knowledge base platform

A knowledge base platform for students to study for free with very elegant design and intuitive functionality.

Dzango Admin — Admin panel for dzango employee and administration management

An admin panel that is designed to manage and handle all the employee data and administration detail in dzangotech with real time notification and interactive UI.

TrueTeaching - Admin teach / Substitute teacher recruitment platform

I worked as a full stack dev on Angular and Python from True Teaching. The tech stack was old and it was a challenge to upgrade their old modules and migrate them to new modules while keeping the test coverage more or same. It was a fun and challenging task and gave me knowledge on package upgrade handling.

Hiboo.io — The tool for modern equipment management teams.

Currently working as a MERN stack developer on Hiboo. We work on creating a multi-source data parsing system and workers driven crawlers and parsers to build an all in one type of environment for vehicle holders to see their data at one place.

SlimWiki v2.0 — Wiki management

Worked as full stack developer for building the new version of <u>slimwiki.com</u> in react and nodejs. Solved the editor problems and migrated to build our own CMS system for the wiki creation/update. Added subscription system and data management and deploy via amazon services and migrated the existing services to AWS.

Makro — Ecommerce Platform, Thailand

Help build the new frontend UI for the new makro.pro. Worked on the backend microservice for the product and search service. Moved the queues to the AWS SQS and created a new search and product suggestions algorithm for the site, updated existing search system for thai text support and implemented sophisticated microservices for processing lots of events analytics to provide relevant products to users. Currently working as full stack dev and working with the Data Science team for improving search and recommendations. I have helped develop very competitive search recommendation ML models and deliver a very good search mechanism for Thai searches which are not well researched in the market for Thai languages.

AWARDS AND EXPERIENCES

Organizer of IT fiesta 2018/2019 – one of the greatest IT fest in Bangalore where we have thousands of participants participating in different IT events.

I have been part of many hackathons events for creating real time node application to communicate with IOT devices

Stripe Certified Developer - I am working as a certified stripe developer since 2023

LANGUAGES

English, Nepali